Help?
救 救
Please help.
救个命啊
Let's go!
跑吧
Right now.
就趁现在
Listen to me.
听我指挥
Who's gone?
谁走了
Meng'an.
梦安走了
She's in a hurry.
早上着急
Before going to work,
上班之前
she'll pay a visit to her father.
她还得去看她爸一眼
No way!
不行不行
She hasn't taken the medicine!
这个药还没吃呢
She won't!
药不吃了
I... I'll take it.
我 我吃吧
Nonsense!
打你
You take it for what?
你吃什么
Let me tell you.
我跟你说啊
Inform me as soon as she's back.
她晚上回来马上通知我
I'll boil the medicine for her.
我给她热药
Two times a day.
早一包 晚一包
Adhere strictly to my prescription.
一包都不能少
Do you hear me?
听见了没有
See?
你看
The dosage is for half a month.
这是半个月的量
Why didn't you knock the door?
你怎么不敲门呢
For what?
敲什么门啊
You're not bare to the waist.
你又没光膀子
I'm your sister.
我是你姐
What do you want?
你什么事
Where are you going?
你干吗去啊
Going for work!
我上班去
Get dressed,
赶快穿好衣服
and talk with me.
出来跟你谈谈
Five minutes.
五分钟
Hurry up.
抓紧时间
Sit down.
坐下
Just spit it out.
你说嘛
Sis,
姐
I'm in my forties.
我也四十好几的人了
Don't treat me like a kid!
你别再管头管脚的了
But you'll always be my brother.
你多大都是我弟弟
Just say it.
说吧
You say first.
你先说
Say what?
我说什么
Our family maxim.
家训
Parental and fraternal bonds
父子合则家不散
unite family members all.
兄弟合则家不分
Exactly!
对嘛
A peaceful family will be prosperous,
意思就是家和万事兴
right?
对吧
Our mother died young,
咱妈走得早
and father had to run the clinic alone.
咱爸一个人操持着医馆
All household chores
这家里大大小小的事
had been my responsibility.
都落到我一个人头上了
Before our father passed away,
咱爸临走前
he asked Ouyang to marry into our family.
让欧阳成了上门女婿
He ordered me
交代我
to discipline you,
让我好好管你
so that you would be a talent.
让你成才
You didn't disappoint us.
你挺争气的
I never worried about your study.
学习 没让我操过心
Afterwards,
这后来呢
you married Meng'an, a good wife.
又娶了梦安这个好媳妇
See?
你看
What a happy life!
这小日子过得不错嘛
For these years,
这么多年
I've never disturbed your life.
我没打扰过你们吧
Well,
不
what's your key point?
你要说的关键是什么
It's the key period now.
现在是关键时刻
The key period of what?
什么关键时刻
It's the key period of our Li family
现在就是我们李家
to raise offspring now.
开枝散叶的关键时刻
Get it?
懂吗
There are not many
人这一辈子
key periods in one's life.
关键时刻不多的
We can only count them
一个手伸出来
with four fingers.
能数得过来的
Birth,
生
age,
老
illness,
病
and death.
死
Birth ranks the first.
生排在第一位
Li Lin,
李临
you should pick up your spirits!
你要打起精神来
Why? Do I look discouraged?
我很精神啊
Why must I pick up my spirits?
我打起精神干什么
I'm not pregnant!
我也不能生啊
Don't beat around the bush!
行了吧你
Though Meng'an is pregnant,
梦安怀孕
you don't want to keep the baby,
你们不想要这个孩子
do you?
对吧
Of course we'll keep the baby!
哪有 没有的事啊
From whom did you hear the rumor?
你听谁说的
It's none of your business.
你管我听谁说的呢
I'll forget about the truth
怀孕的事你不告诉我
that you didn't tell me.
我不跟你计较
I understand that you want to
你们瞒着我
hide it away from me.
我也可以理解
In our opinion,
我们觉得吧
let nature take its course.
就是要顺其自然
The baby appears unexpectedly.
这个孩子是个意外
If God keeps it,
如果老天给
we'll keep it;
那我们就接着
if it's not strong enough,
如果老天不给
we have no other choice.
那我们也没办法
How come?
怎么没办法
Our Li Family has studied
我们李家是
TCM for generations.
祖传中医世家了
No doubt we have choices!
我们当然有办法啊
It is true that
这 我们李家
we've studied TCM for long,
是祖传中医世家
but you're not a doctor.
但是你不是大夫
Do you have ways to keep the baby?
你有什么办法
I am the way.
我就是办法
I've arranged everything properly.
我都已经安排好了
I arranged Lanxiang
我已经安排了
to look after your father-in-law.
让兰香照顾你老丈人
As for me,
我呢 这次
I'll stay here
留下来
to look after you.
照顾你们
You?
你
Yes.
对
Stay here?
留下来
I have my duty to stay here,
我这次来 任务在身
which is to help the Li Family
就是为了咱李家
to
开
raise
枝
the
散
offspring!
叶
What takes you so long?
怎么那么长时间啊
I'm going late for work.
上班都要迟到了
You ran away,
你是跑了
but I failed.
我没跑了啊
She was disciplining me back there.
按那儿被她一通说呀
I knew it.
我看出来了
She's prepared
她是做好了
to stay in our house.
安营扎寨的准备
Lanxiang is unreliable!
这兰香 太不靠谱了
Forget it.
算了
Anyway,
反正都这样了
we can face the challenge.
我们就迎难而上
Don't worry.
你放心
I'll let her go back.
我跟她说 让她回去
Is it appropriate?
不好吧
I think so.
什么不好吧
When you gave birth to Yunjie,
你生云阶那会儿
she was in our house, remember?
她在我们家里 你忘了
Like a backseat driver.
一通地指手画脚
Weren't you angry?
你不生气
I was.
生了
See?
对啊
But we were young back then.
但那时候不是年轻吗
In the twenties,
二十多岁
we had big egos.
正是做自我的时候
Things are different now.
现在不一样了呀
If someone can give me a hand now,
你要真有个人能帮帮我
I'll be glad.
我也挺高兴的
Besides, back then,
再说了 那时候
some of her words made sense.
姐说的很多话还是对的
She's the head nurse, anyway.
毕竟人家是护士长嘛
How ridiculous!
什么护士长
Working in her own clinic,
自家诊所
she can be the head of clinic!
说自己是所长都行
Well,
不是
I'm afraid she'll cause trouble
主要就是我是怕她在家
to you.
给你添乱
I admit she's a good person,
我姐这个人是好人
but disregards social distance.
就是没有分寸感
While I was getting myself dressed,
这刚才我换衣服的时候
she came in
门也不敲
without knocking on the door,
咣当一下就进来了
giving me a start.
我吓一跳
So embarrassing!
多尴尬是吧
If you were not pregnant,
你要是没怀孕
she could live here
她在我们家
as long as she wished.
想住多久住多久
It doesn't matter,
无所谓的
though sometimes she might be bossy.
无非就是她管着点我们
Things are different now
现在不一样了
since a baby comes.
怀着孩子
If in case that
那往后如果万一
something wrong happens to you,
你身体上再有什么情况
let alone going to work,
你还想上班
she won't even allow you to go out!
她连门都不让你出
Don't you trust me?
你不信啊
I do, I do.
那还 还是信的
In that case,
那要不你回头
you try to ask her.
试探试探她
Fine.
行
I'll have a try.
我试探试探
Don't worry.
你放心吧
I won't infuriate her.
我会注意方式方法的
If she doesn't want to leave,
她要是不想走的话
don't be too tough.
你也别硬来
I won't.
那不会
Unlike her,
我不是她
I know the limit.
我有分寸
The job can't be lost!
这不上班肯定是不行
How dare you bring a phone here?
学校不许玩手机
I'll take it!
没收啦
My heart missed a beat!
你吓死我了
Last night,
昨天晚上
were it not me saving the situation,
多亏我力挽狂澜
my mother might give up
不然我妈这老二
the baby!
就不生了
Don't you believe me?
你不信啊
Do you know how I told my mother?
你猜我怎么跟我妈谈的
Last night,
昨天晚上
my parents didn't
我妈和我爸
come back until midnight.
半夜才回来的
I was waiting in the living room.
我就在客厅等他俩
Even so, my mother scolded me,
我妈还数落我
"Good for you, Li Yunjie!
好你个李云阶啊
How dare you stay up late?"
这么晚了还不睡 是吗
Do you know what I said?
你猜我怎么说的
What did you say?
怎么说的
"Woman,
女人
I have a word with you.
我要跟你谈谈
The baby in your womb
你肚子里这个宝宝
must be kept.
要生
Dad dares not tell you,
我爸不敢跟你说
but I do.
我敢跟你说
I won't make any recession,
我今天就把话撂这儿了
and it all depends on your attitude."
就看你什么态度了
What did your mom say?
那你妈怎么说
My mom said,
我妈说
"Good for you, Li Yunjie!
好你个李云阶呀
How dare you
胆儿肥了
speak to me like that?"
敢这么跟我说话
But she promised me eventually.
不过她最后还是答应了
In our home,
我们家呀
my dad's not a decision-maker,
我爸根本就不扛事
and he discusses everything with her.
都得靠我跟我妈谈
How tiring!
可累了
You're so naive!
你就是幼稚
Afterwards,
以后啊
your life will be miserable.
有你哭的
Stop being so serious!
别跟我撂狠话了
The baby is my little sister.
那是我妹妹
Just leave it to me.
你就甭管了
How do you know it's a she?
你怎么知道是妹妹呢
What if it's a he?
万一是个弟弟
You are doomed to be miserable!
你就有的哭喽
It'll be fine.
那也没关系啊
My dad will be my supporter.
有我爸给我撑腰呢
Anyway,
再说了
everything at home
我们家的局面
is under my control.
都在我的掌控之中
Stop bragging!
行了你 你就吹吧
Under your control?
还都在我的掌控之中
Woman, I have a word with you!
女人 我要跟你谈谈
I'm so afraid!
我好怕怕呀
Stop it!
行了 行了
Little Watermelon, cheer up!
小西瓜 加油
Cheer up!
加油
Little Watermelon,
小西瓜
mom's visiting you.
妈妈来看你了
Your mom is a beauty.
妈妈是个大美女
Once you can see her,
第一眼看见妈妈以后
you'll be a beauty yourself!
我们长大就是个小美女
Cheer up, Little Watermelon!
加油 小西瓜
Little Watermelon?
叫什么小西瓜呀
Who gave her such a name?
谁起的名字啊
Darling,
老婆
the name is given by Xiongxiong.
这是熊熊给起的名字哦
Given such a name,
小朋友起这样的名字
She'll be easily raised.
好养活的
Our baby is a girl,
我们是女孩子
so it sounds terrible
叫小西瓜
to be called Little Watermelon!
难听死了
Sweet.
甜
Sweet girl.
甜妹子
Darling,
老婆老婆
does your wound hurt?
你是不伤口疼啊
I'm so sorry.
真的对不起
So sorry about that.
对不起 对不起啊
It's all my fault.
都怪我 都怪我
Darling.
老婆
If you didn't sign your name,
要不是你签字
my belly wouldn't have suffered!
我也不用挨这一刀
Darling,
老婆
I had no gut to sign my name.
我哪有那胆签字
Let me tell you,
我跟你说
it was your sister.
都是你姐逼的我
You didn't sign your name?
是不是你签的
I... I just offered up
我 我只是贡献了
a hand.
手
Darling.
老婆
I'm so sorry.
老婆对不起啊
Take care. It's my fault.
乖啊 老婆 对不起
Why so mysterious?
什么事啊
Why not talk about it
不能在办公室说
in our office?
非要到这儿来说
I decided
我打算
to tell Mr. Zhang the truth.
找老张摊牌了
Haven't we decided
咱俩不刚商量完这事
not to tell him?
先不说吗
Sooner or later.
早晚的事嘛
In these days,
其实这两天
I was wondering
我动过不要
if I should keep the baby.
这个孩子的念头
But my father was ill,
但是因为我爸生病
and my sister gave a premature birth,
我妹妹早产
which made me realize
确实让我觉得
how vulnerable life is.
生命很脆弱
Every life
每个生命
should be respected,
都应该得到尊重
and taken good care of,
需要好好爱护
so Li Lin and I
所以我跟李临
made a deal
也商量好了
to keep the baby
这个孩子
the God gave us.
我们要
Though we are not rich,
虽然不是大富大贵之家
and our energy has decreased,
精力可能也不比从前
we're determined to
但是我们还是决定
have a try.
拼一把
I support you.
我支持你
We should really
那这事
think about the issue now.
咱得好好盘算盘算了
What's your idea?
你有什么想法
I have only one underling,
目前我手底下
who is Ling Meichuan.
只有凌美川一个人
If I tell Mr. Zhang the truth,
如果我找老张摊牌的话
he'll definitely
他一定会
find another Deputy Director,
再找一个副总监
whose professional ability
且这个人的业务能力
will be great.
会很强
Apparently,
很显然
there is no candidate
公司里现在
for such a position.
没有这样的人选
Who do you think will be?
那你觉得会是谁呢
I don't know.
我不知道
Whoever he or she is,
但是不管是谁
it must be guaranteed that
必须要保证
after my maternity leave,
我休完产假回来之后
I can still
仍然可以坐在
keep my position.
这个位置上
I love it when you're competitive.
我就爱看你开卷
But it's not the right time
我现在肯定不是
to be competitive.
卷的时候啊
What I need to do now is
我现在需要做的是
mapping out a strategy,
运筹帷幄
biding my time,
韬光养晦
and arranging everything well.
安排布局好
I want to discuss with you
想找你商量的是
if neither of the Deputy Directors
如果两个副总监
is my underling,
都不是我的人的话
I'll need another hand
我还需要一个帮手
to help me stabilize my work.
来帮我稳定业务中心
I'm wondering
你看从你那儿
if it is possible for him
有没有可能
to create a position
再给我批一个
for my assistant.
职务出来呢
Director Assistant!
总监助理
I'll ask Wanzhen.
我去问问婉真姐
Wanzhen,
婉真姐
may I ask you a question?
我跟您打听点事呗
Go ahead.
你说
Did you buy the financial product
咱们公司理财产品
of our company?
你买了吗
What's the matter?
怎么了
My boyfriend and I
我跟我男朋友
tend to get some money for it,
想凑一笔钱买点
so I'm curious about
就想打听打听
how much everyone bought.
看看大家都买了多少
It's hard to earn money now.
现在挣钱不容易
Don't put all your eggs
你不要把鸡蛋
into one basket.
放在一个篮子里
In fact,
其实
we want to use the earned money
我们是想赚了这笔钱
to buy a car.
换辆车呢
How can I make it clear?
怎么说呢
The investment product
这个投资理财啊
has risks.
是有风险的
I suggest you
我建议你
to invest sensibly.
还是得适当投入吧
Fine, I get it.
好 我知道了
Thank you, Wanzhen.
谢谢婉真姐
Why do you still work during a break?
休息时候你都这么拼啊
Wanzhen,
婉真姐啊
how I envy you
我是真羡慕你
for being so wealthy!
家里条件这么好
Financial product is nothing to you,
你不买就算了
but the only way for us ordinary people
可是我们这些小职员呢
to make a fortune.
就这点财路
We can never compare with you,
跟你这种
a wealthy wife
离了婚打土豪的
divorcing a tyrant!
阔太太比不了
I've worked in the company
而且我在公司
for over five years,
有五六年了
so I quite know
我还是挺了解
the company.
这个公司的
The yield you despise
你看不上的这点收益
means a lot to us,
那对于我们来说
which is a great amount.
可是一大笔横财呢
It's a real estate company,
我们是地产公司
and selling houses is our duty.
卖房子是正职
If you don't need to sale,
但如果你不想开单
why don't you
那你能不能
give me some clients
把你手里的那些
who can afford
阔太太呀
buying real estate?
老板的资源给我
I want to sale.
我还想开几单呢
If you really want to sell houses,
如果你真想卖房子
I can introduce some to you.
我可以介绍给你
If
如果
you want to sell financial products,
你想卖理财产品
let me tell you,
我告诉你
no way.
不行
Forget about it.
你算了吧
How could you give up
你的那些优质客户
the rich clients to me?
你舍得给我吗
You're holding them tightly,
你手里攥得紧紧的
even Mr. Qian.
你连钱总都不舍得
As for me,
我呀
I'll earn the money
还是去挣你那些
you despise!
瞧不起的小钱吧
Come on,
走
it's my treat.
请你吃饭
Darling,
老伴
could you check how much money
你给看看咱们卡里
do we have in our deposit card?
还有多少钱啊
It's a merit, of course!
当然是好事了
Fine, I'll touch you later.
行了 回去跟你说
I'll hang up.
挂了啊
Okay.
好
Come here.
来来来
Mr. Sun.
孙主任
I'm looking for you.
我找你呢 来
Please have a seat.
你快快 坐坐
Wanzhen,
婉真啊
your major is finance,
你以前不是学过金融吗
so I want you to have a look
我想让你帮我看看
at the financial product
咱们公司的
in our company.
理财收益怎么样
I want to buy some.
我想买点
The quota can't ignore
你说我们行政岗啊
Department of Administration, right?
也要有点额度 对不对
Mr. Sun,
孙主任
I suggest you
我建议您啊
not to buy it.
还是别买
Why not?
不是
Vice Manager Qian has bought a lot,
钱副总都买了很多
as well as other top managers.
其他高管都买了
It's very profitable!
说是很赚钱的
Don't worry.
你别怕
Our company won't bear any crisis.
公司不会有问题的
The financial product
这个理财产品啊
is based on
它是根据
the individual asset ratio.
个人资产配比来的
Can you imagine their income?
那高管人家收入多呀
It doesn't work for ordinary people!
我们普通人可不行啊
Well, I've promised
不是 钱总啊
the order given by Mr. Qian.
下的指示我已经答应了
We have to buy some.
咱多少得买点吧
You see,
你看
those top managers
几个高管
have earned quite a lot,
人家收益都挺高的
so we can't fall behind, can we?
咱也不能落后 对不对
How about that?
这样吧
Mr. Sun,
孙主任
do we have
咱们公司
any financial statement
近几年的财务报表
in previous years?
都在这儿吧
They're all here.
在这儿
I'll check it out,
我先看一下
and make a judgment, okay?
然后再做判断 好不好
No problem.
没问题
They're all here.
都在这儿呢
Two years' statements.
去年的和前年的
I've heard that
我可听说
Mr. Qian gave you a hard time
你不买理财
for not buying any product.
钱总给你穿小鞋了
That's not true.
没有的事
Mr. Qian
这钱总呢
gave me time to consider.
是给我时间考虑
He permits me to buy it
他想让我上完那个
after I finish my securities training.
证券培训班以后再说
What a nerd you are!
你是不是书读多了
Don't you see?
脑子都死板了
Your major is finance.
你以前不是学过金融吗
Since I've studied securities,
那就是因为我学过证券
I'm more cautious about it
所以在我没搞清楚之前
before I figure everything out.
我不能随便入手呀
Okay, keep it.
行 那你先看着
Think about it.
考虑考虑
Hello, Grace.
喂 格蕾丝
May I ask you a question?
有一件事我想问一下
About the finance of real estate.
就是关于地产金融的
Do you have any time?
你现在有时间吗
You're pregnant!
你怀孕了
Really?
真的假的
Mr. Zhang,
张总
it's good news.
这可是好事啊
It means our company
这说明咱们公司
is a blessed place!
是个福地呀
What's wrong with you?
你有什么想不开的
I mean,
不是
in your age, it's...
你关键你这年龄这
a high risk.
高危
Are you going to keep it?
还要吗
Of course.
那得要啊
In her age,
她这么大岁数了
what a bless
还能怀二胎
to have a second baby!
多不容易啊
That's right.
也对啊
Well,
这
sorry.
对不起啊
Should I congratulate you?
我是不是应该恭喜你啊
Thanks, Mr. Zhang.
谢谢张总
But our company
关键现在这公司
has so many things to do.
这千头万绪的这么多事
What should we do...
你说这这这
to continue our work?
这下边工作安排
What's your idea?
怎么弄啊 你这
I do have an idea,
我是有一些想法的
so I asked Rachel
所以叫瑞秋过来
to discuss with you about it.
想跟您一起商量一下
I see.
是这样啊
Well,
就是
in my age,
我现在这个年龄呢
it's true to be hard
确实怀孕
to be pregnant,
挺不容易的
and the energy cannot compare
但是精力肯定
with that before.
也不如从前
In my opinion,
我在想
rather than doing my original work,
与其这样的话
I prefer to
要不我就
resign.
辞职
Nice try!
你想得美
Let alone the six-month work time,
别说你还能工作六个月
the maternity leave is
那产假也就
mere 128 days.
一百二十八天
If you resign now,
你这个时候走
you're putting Mr. Zhang
你不把张总
in a big trouble!
往火坑里推吗
How come?
怎么会呢
You see,
你看
the lactation period
孕产妇哺乳期
is protected by the law.
那是受劳动法保护的
If you leave now,
你这时候走
not only is the law violated,
咱先不说劳动法
but also the reputation
这传出去
of Mr. Zhang
你让张总
will be ruined!
以后怎么做人呢
Let me tell you,
我告诉你
no way for you to resign!
你辞职都不行
Is that true?
是这样吗
Then that's a big problem.
那就有点麻烦了哈
Although we have a Deputy Director
这内容部
in the Content Department,
虽然现在有一个副总监
Meichuan
但是美川吧
has never done content
她这么多年
all through the years.
一直都没有做过内容
I'll try my best to help her grow.
我当然会尽力带她啊
But,
可是
no matter how hard I try,
就算我全力以赴的话
it will take long for her
估计她上手
to fully carry the burden.
也没那么快呀
Then recruit a new one.
那从外面再招一个呗
What?
招什么呀
A Deputy Director?
副总监吗
If you hire another Deputy Director,
你招一个副总监
he or she must be
你怎么着都得找一个
familiar with content,
懂内容的
and have good professional ability.
业务好的呀
I consent to what Mr. Zhang said.
我同意张总这个想法啊
But there's something else,
但是还有一点哈
which is,
就是
two Deputy Directors,
两个副总监
with one not familiar with work,
一个不懂业务
while the other not familiar to us,
一个是外来的和尚
isn't it unstable
这在实操上面会不会
if the work
还是有一些
starts to unravel?
不稳定因素啊
How about
要不
choosing one from our company?
咱们从内部再提拔一个
At least, from the perspective of
至少在忠诚度
fidelity, credibility
和信任度上
and work proficiency,
还有实操的层面上
it will be much more reliable.
会稳妥很多
How about Jiaojiao?
那个娇娇怎么样
That girl?
娇娇
I think Yu is also a good choice.
我觉得小于也是可以的
For God's sake!
得了吧 你俩这个提的
Neither can't even compete with Mu!
还不如阿木呢
Then choose Mu.
那提阿木啊
Deputy Director is too much for him.
提也不能提太高
It's appropriate for him
刚给他加完薪
to work more with higher salary.
多干点是可以的
I think,
主要是
he can assist two Deputy Directors.
协调两个副总监的工作
How about Director Assistant?
总监助理吧
What do you think, Mr. Zhang?
您说呢 张总
Then choose Mu.
那就阿木吧
We'll arrange that.
那我们就去安排
Have a good rest!
好好保胎啊
Is that your scheme?
我怎么觉得你们两个
Have a rest!
保胎去吧
Let's go.
走走走
Wendy?
温蒂
Why are you here?
你怎么在这儿
I'm looking for Grace.
我来找格蕾丝
Do you have any plan
有没有
to be back in our financial industry?
重回金融行业的打算
Yes.
有啊
Marvelous!
太好了 终于有了
What are you waiting for?
那还等什么
Come to me as soon as you can.
赶紧来我这儿
I need trusted advisors.
我这儿特别缺人手
I've learnt a few about your company.
你公司我了解过
Like a dark horse since the beginning,
一直是黑马的姿态
you have led the investment
又领投了
of new sales,
新销售
manufacture,
制造业
and Cultural and Creative Industries,
文创等好几个板块的
which are all unicorn companies.
独角兽公司
You've done adequate work!
功课做得很足啊
Work for me.
那就来吧
My email is on my business card,
名片上有我的邮箱
and the headhunter is acquainted
猎头和我们公司人事
with my HR.
也很熟
I know, Mr. Zhou.
我知道 周总
I'm making preparations
我现在呢 在做准备
for an opportunity.
等机会
What for?
做什么准备
One can never be well prepared.
人的准备是永远不够的
A chance already appears.
现在机会就在你眼前
I hope you can
我希望你能
accept my invitation.
接受我的邀请
I'm preparing
我打算啊
for a certificate.
先拿到敲门砖
As soon as I get it,
只要拿到了
I'll knock on the gate of Yaohui Co..
我马上来敲耀辉的大门
Alright.
行
I'll be waiting for your knock.
我等你来敲我的门
Okay.
好啊
Goodbye.
我先走了
Wanzhen.
婉真
The materials you need.
你要的资料
Thank you.
谢谢
The materials
这些呢
are disclosed financial statements
都是金融市场上
in the financial market.
公开的财报资料了
Excellent!
好 太好了
What do you need them for?
你要这些干吗呀
I want to know
我想了解一下
the financial condition
华謃地产公司
of Huaxing Real Estate Co..
在市场上的资金情况
So you intend to
看来你是打算
be back to finance.
重回老本行了
When are you coming back?
什么时候杀回来
Soon.
快了
Everything's here.
都在这儿了
Thank you.
谢谢啊
You're welcome.
不客气
I feel pity for the boss.
当老板真不容易啊
Is there any company
你说这其他公司
like ours?
也像咱们这样吗
Probably.
应该吧
It's said that the boss
不都说老板
is working for the employees.
是给员工打工的吗
He consents to me
那我内容部提案
every time I make a proposal.
哪次他不是听我的呀
Oh, I feel pity for him.
突然有点同情他
Who came up with the idea?
那这主意谁出的
Whom am I doing this for?
那我为了谁呀
It's all for you.
我还不为了你
Can he recognize it?
你说他能看出来吗
No matter how,
那看出来看不出来
a deal is a deal.
不也都这样了
I'm doing this for our company.
我是真为了公司着想
I have professional integrity!
我是有职业操守的
You didn't let him down.
那你还是对得起他的
Of course.
那是
Does it mean
是不是从今天起
you'll retreat to the back line?
我就要退居二线了呀
Not bad.
也挺好
You'll have time to have a rest.
放放权 养养身体
It's time to raise your soldiers.
培养一下自己的团队
You can't always in the front line.
你也不能总在一线干吧
What a good chance
正好趁着这期间
to rest.
休息休息
I suddenly feel down.
突然有点失落
Why do I feel so?
是怎么回事
Is it because I can't adapt to it?
是不是我还不太能适应
Everything
任何事情
needs time to adjust.
都需要适应一段过程
It won't take too long.
大不了时间长点
How long will it be?
得多长啊
Yummy!
好吃 好吃
I'm glad you like it.
好吃多吃点
Are you sure I can eat this?
你确定我能吃这个吗
As long as it's not too much.
少吃点没事的
You'll feel good after eating sweets,
你吃完甜食心情还好呢
which is good for your recovery.
能更好地恢复元气
That's true.
就是嘛
I desire for the sweets,
我就特别想吃甜的
but I'm not allowed here.
他们都不让我吃
They only give me
成天给我搞点什么
plain food.
清汤寡水的东西
Yuck!
难吃死了
Oh, my darling.
可怜兮兮的
My baby was sent to
你说我的宝宝
thermostatic chamber after birth.
刚出生就进了恒温室
I don't know
也不知道现在
if she can make it.
恢复得怎么样
I feel so worried!
心里可担心了
Don't worry.
别担心
Being sent to the thermostatic chamber
这宝宝进了恒温室
enables her to be taken good care of.
是为了得到更好的照顾
Besides, we have nurses.
这不还有护士吗
When I gave birth to
我当时
Wanwan and Zhenzhen,
生婉婉 真真的时候
each twin
那可是双胞胎
was only 1.5 kilograms,
那单个才三斤多
so they were also sent there.
也进了恒温室
I was extremely worried back then,
我当时也特别特别担心
but look at them now.
但现在你看
They can't be
她们健健康康
healthy enough!
活蹦乱跳的呢
The second child
我觉得二胎啊
brought me a different attitude.
真的不一样
I lost my courage now.
我现在胆子可小了
When I gave birth to Xiongxiong,
那那会儿生熊熊的时候
how reckless I was!
我心可大了
And luckily, of course,
我觉得他也皮实
he's healthy,
没事
and I recovered soon.
我自己恢复得也快
But now,
现在
the instant I think of my daughter,
现在一想到我闺女
lying in the chamber
自己一个人
on her own,
躺在恒温室里
with no one caressing her,
孤孤零零的
I feel so painful!
我心里可难受
I can't agree more.
我特别能理解
Your postpartum hormone level
你现在是
is unstable now,
产后激素水平不稳定
so you're too worried.
过于担心
With so many doctors and nurses,
这医院那么多医生护士
you have no reason to worry.
你担心什么
The most important thing
你现在最重要的是
is to cheer yourself up,
愉悦心情
so as to recover soon.
好好地恢复
Keep a good mood.
保持一个好的心情
A good mood.
好的心情
If there's anything you want to eat,
你要是想吃什么
tell me secretly,
你就悄悄地告诉我
and I'll bring them quietly.
我再悄悄给你送过来
My uncle,
叔啊
have more bananas.
这香蕉您得多吃一点啊
Good for your defecation.
这这 通便
Come on.
来
Open your mouth.
叔 张嘴
There. Have more fruit.
对 水果多吃点
Come on.
来
Yes.
对
Is that all?
这 不想吃了
My uncle,
叔
no way.
不行啊
Turn your head to me.
转过来 转过来
We have to eat it.
咱得吃呀 叔
Or you'll suffer a lot
你上不出厕所来
if you can't poop,
憋得满脸通红
which breaks my heart!
我看着都心疼
It's good for defecation.
这个通便
Don't be capricious.
不能任性 叔
By taking adequate nutrition,
这营养好了
you can recover sooner.
咱恢复得就快啊
Lanxiang.
兰香姐
Oh, Meng'an.
梦安来了
Open your mouth.
张嘴
Did you have your breakfast?
怎么样 吃过早饭了没
Yes, I did.
吃过了吃过了
You did?
吃过了啊
So did my father?
我爸也吃了
Yes, he did.
吃了 吃了 吃了
He did?
吃了
He's eating fruit now.
吃水果呢
Have more.
来 再多吃点
I'll do this.
我来喂吧
Okay.
行
Do you want to stop?
是不是不想吃了
We'll stop now.
那就不吃了
Take it away.
收了吧 收了吧
Okay, fine.
好 行行行
Take it off.
摘
Spit it out.
来 吐
I know.
不想吃
That's too much!
塞这么些呢
Don't be angry with her.
你别生气啊
She has never attended to patients.
兰香姐没照顾过病人
I'll tell her later
回头我跟她说
to feed you more slowly.
以后喂你的时候慢点喂
She used to look after Yunjie
原来她照顾云阶
very well.
照顾得可好了
I'll let her
回头我就让她
look after you like that,
像照顾云阶那样照顾你
okay?
好吗
Have you heard of it?
听说了吧
Mengxin had another baby.
心心生了
A girl.
女孩
Over 2.5 kilograms.
五斤多
Her skin's so fair,
可白了
and her eyes are big,
大眼睛 卡巴卡巴的
like Mengxin when she was little.
特别像心心小时候
Xiongxiong
熊熊
gave her an infant name,
还给她起了个小名
called Little Watermelon.
叫小西瓜
He said
说
the Little Watermelon is sweet.
西瓜甜
Are you glad now?
高兴了
Keep it.
生
Are you sure?
真生啊
How can I keep it with you being ill?
那你这样我怎么生啊
Li Lin and I
那我跟李临
are both working.
可都是双职工
How can we take care of the baby?
生了孩子谁给我带呀
I cannot trust my mom.
交给我妈我可不放心
It doesn't work, does it?
不行是不是
Will you help me?
你带呀
I will.
我带
Then, get better soon,
那你得赶快好起来
so you can help me raise the baby.
才能给我带孩子
Right?
知道吗
My darling.
媳妇
We can eat nothing
别的 不吃咱就不吃
but the soup.
汤要喝了
Our mom cooked it for you.
妈亲手给你煲的
It's very nutritious!
小火慢炖 营养丰富
Mengxin.
心
I don't eat it.
不喝
My darling.
老婆
The C-section
咱是剖腹产
brought you a wound,
身上有疤
and the soup is good
要恢复元气
for your recovery.
对身体有好处
Who caused it?
谁造成的
I'm asking you a question!
我就问你谁造成的
No way.
不行
I'll drink the soup, and eat food.
我要喝汤 我要吃饭
I'll recover so as to
我要攒够了力气
get even with Xu Meng'an!
去找许梦安算账
Come on, my darling.
快来 媳妇
That's right.
好嘞
Only when you eat more
多吃饭 多喝汤
can you be recovered
咱攒够力气
to get even with your sister!
找你姐算账去
How could she do that?
太不像话
Eat more food,
多吃饭
and drink more soup.
多喝汤
You want me to eat
你让我吃饱了
and drink
喝饱了
so as to feed your baby like a cow,
好给你的娃当奶牛
don't you?
是不是
I don't have the gut!
老婆 我哪儿敢哪
All I want is to help you recover!
我就是为了让你养伤
We don't need to feed her.
奶水不用喂她
We have formula,
咱有奶粉
which is nutritious
营养搭配
and enough for our baby.
非常的合理
Darling,
老婆
what else do you want to eat?
你还想吃点别的什么
I'll buy it for you.
我给你买去
I want sweets.
我想吃甜的
Steamed buns with wine.
酒酿馒头
Rice with sweat bean sand...
豆沙米粿
Mengxin.
心心
Mom.
妈
Here comes a prolactinist.
通乳师来了
Prolactinist?
什么通乳师啊
I won't do breastfeeding.
我不通乳
My wound hasn't been healed!
我伤口没愈合呢
No way to force me to be a cow!
就想着让我当奶牛啊
Jia Haowen.
贾浩文
We should do this!
得通 得通
Otherwise, you'll have inflammation.
这不通啊 就堵奶了
Get out!
出去
Please get out.
出 出去出去
Take your time.
别急 别急 别急
Get out of here.
快出 出出出去
So sorry for coming here.
谢谢啊 还让你跑一趟
Okay.
好
Goodbye.
慢点啊
Take care.
我不送了啊
Bye-bye.
拜拜
I reckon that Mengxin
我看心心哪
is taking it out on me
这是趁着坐月子
in her postpartum confinement.
跟我撒气呢
Mom, be quiet.
妈 小点声
She was not like that before.
她平时不这样
Don't lie to me!
谁信呢
I've noticed the injury
她把你打那样
made by her.
我没看见啊
When did she hit me?
哪儿打我了
It's just an accident.
这不偶然事件吗
I've also noticed
你对她那个
how obedient you are
巴巴结结的样子
in front of her.
我还不知道啊
You call it obedient?
妈呀 谁巴巴结结的
It's my way to run my family.
这是我治家之道
Don't meddle with it!
您就别掺和了
She's in great pain,
她现在特殊时期
so we have to be obedient.
咱让着她点
For what?
凭什么呀
Do you owe her?
你这一辈子欠她的
Don't you know
她爸怎么病的
how her father
怎么住院
went to hospital?
您不知道啊
Fine.
行了 行了
I see.
我知道了
I'll also be obedient to her.
她说啥就是啥
Just a few months.
反正没几个月嘛
I'll pretend to be obedient.
那我就装呗
I'll do it!
我装
Mom, sorry for
好好好 妈
putting up with her.
您委屈 您受苦
Don't forget your promise.
您自个儿说话 别忘了
I know.
知道了
Mom,
妈
I'll but her some food.
我去给她买点吃的啊
Go ahead.
你去吧
Do you need any?
也给您带点 您吃什么
No need.
不用 不用 不用
Just tell me.
别客气
Go ahead!
快去吧你
I'll go, mom.
我去了 妈
Okay.
你去吧
Massage is the doctor's prescription.
大夫说了 多按摩
You'll get better with it.
能好得快一点
Xu,
老许
get better soon.
快点好
Uncle!
叔
Auntie.
阿姨
Jing is here.
我静姐来了
Sorry for being late.
来晚了
Please forgive me
不好意思 亲家母
for coming here late.
来晚了 我来晚了
Jing,
她大姑
why are you here?
你怎么来了呀
Why did you come here
这么大老远
from far away?
你还跑过来了
Your husband is ill,
亲家都病了
why can't I come here?
你说我能不来吗
Aren't we families?
咱不是一家人吗
Yes.
是是是
Am I right?
是吧
Please have a seat.
来来来 坐坐坐
Sit down.
坐下
What happened to him?
这亲家 什么情况
He had a stroke.
中风啦
Right, the mouth is crooked.
是啊 这嘴都歪了
The doctor said he's much better.
大夫说好多啦
Well, you see,
那个 你看
your husband's ill,
亲家病了
but I can give you nothing
我也帮不上什么忙
except for
这个
the red envelope.
一点小心意
No way!
这个不行
I cannot take your money.
这个我绝对不能收
I really can't!
真不能收
Look at you!
你看你看你看
Take it,
你收不收
or I'll be angry with you!
你不收我跟你翻脸了
Not too much, is it?
一点心意嘛 是吧
Well,
那
it's so kind of you. Thanks.
太有心了 谢谢啊
Come here.
来来来
Let me have a look.
你过来 让我来看看
Hello!
老爷子
Jesus,
天
does he lose his consciousness?
不认人哪
It's alright!
没事
I am Li Jing.
我是李静
Remember?
记得吗
The paternal aunt!
大姑
Yunjie's aunt!
她大姑
Well.
你看
Have a seat.
你坐 你坐
Okay.
这个
Let me see...
我看
Oh, the hand!
这手
Oh, my God!
我天哪
This is so...
这个 这个
Don't worry.
没 没事
I've learnt to cure the disease.
我 我也学过一点
My husband, Ouyang,
那个 我们家老欧阳啊
prescribed some TCM for him.
给老爷子开了点中药
I'll tell you how to take it.
回头我告诉你怎么吃
I'll also tell Lanxiang.
我跟兰香交代一下
Mr. Xu,
老爷子
the post-hospital recovery
出院以后啊 后期康复
can be done
要不然就到我们那个
in our clinic,
中医诊所去怎么样
okay?
行吗
Look at his expression.
你看这表情
Is it yes or no?
是乐意还是不乐意
A stroke like this
这个像你这种情况
needs special treatment.
后期康复很重要啊
Okay.
好好好
No problem.
没问题 没问题啊
He dislikes others touching him.
他不太喜欢别人碰他
Okay, I see.
好嘞好嘞 我知道
I get it.
知道了知道了
I came here, for one reason
那个我这次来啊
is to pay a visit to him.
一是看看老爷子
Right.
对
For another, I'll visit Mengxin.
顺便还看看心心
Most importantly,
最主要的呢
Meng'an is pregnant,
不是梦安怀孕了吗
so,
我呀
I won't leave until Meng'an gave birth
得待到梦安把孩子生了
and finish her postpartum confinement.
踏踏实实地把月子坐完
Three months!
三个月
A long period!
大月子
Not a single day should be missed!
一天都不能少
Three months?
三个月
Well,
那个
when has Meng'an
梦安什么时候
asked for help?
让人照顾过呀
There's no need.
那个真用不着
We have Lanxiang
我跟你说这不有
here.
兰香呢吗
Don't worry.
你放心
Everything is arranged.
我都安排好啦
Mr. Xu,
老爷子
I won't touch you.
我不碰你 你放心
Do you like the meal
是不是特别喜欢
made by Lanxiang?
吃兰香做的菜啊
See?
你看 你看
After you're discharged from hospital,
老爷子出院以后啊
I'll let Lanxiang
我就让兰香啊
attend to your diet and daily life.
来照顾你们的饮食起居
No.
不用
No need.
真不用
Don't worry.
你放心吧
As long as I'm here,
有我在啊
everything can be arranged.
什么事都安排好了呢
I should visit Mengxin now.
我呀 还得去看看心心
How blessed she is
她生了一儿一女
to have a boy and a girl!
你说多有福气呀
I'd like to take a piece of luck.
我不得去沾沾喜气啊
Well,
那个什么
Mengxin has just done a C-section.
心心啊 刚做了剖腹产
It is not convenient for you
你这个时候去见她
to visit her.
不太方便
It's okay. Just some presents.
没事 我放下东西就走
Alright.
行了
You should
那你那个
have a good rest.
好好休息啊
Wish you...
祝你
No...
别
recover soon.
早日康复
I'll leave now.
好 我先走了
Okay.
好好好
Well.
好 你看
See you later.
再见都会
Okay.
好
Recover soon.
早日康复
I have a word with Lanxiang.
我 我跟兰香 交代几句
Okay.
好
Goodbye.
好 老爷子
Let's go.
好 走
I'll be back soon.
我马上回来啊
Don't worry. She's gone.
没事没事 走了
She'll visit Mengxin.
她说去看心心
I'm afraid she'll bring her trouble.
不会又添什么乱吧
Don't worry.
没事 我
It's me!
我
His physical condition now
老爷子现在这个情况啊
needs your patience and care.
你得尽心一点
Thank you.
辛苦
Don't be afraid.
别怕吃苦
I'm not.
不怕 姐
See?
你看
Meng'an didn't detest
当时梦安不嫌弃
my family condition.
我家里那个情况
She asked me to stay,
把我留下来
and gave me a lot of things
给我送了那么多东西
including red envelopes,
还给我塞红包
so I'm so grateful
姐 你们一家子
for your whole family!
都是我的贵人
I'll do my best!
我一定好好干
Don't worry.
放心
Meng'an is a good person.
梦安这个人呀 真好
Yes.
是
She has good virtues.
懂礼数
However,
不过
you also did a good merit!
你也立功啦
No, I...
没有 我
Well...
这
You helped Meng'an keep her baby.
你帮梦安保胎
No, I...
没有 我这
And you informed me secretly.
还给我打小报告
No,
不
my sister.
姐
Never tell anybody
我给你打电话的事
about the dial!
可千万别告诉别人啊
What am I? A fool?
我傻呀
However,
不过
I thought
我后来想
I didn't tell you anything,
我也没说什么
but
我就
a super faint hint
稍微那么一点点暗示
was instantly noticed by you.
你一下子就听出来了
Who am I?
我谁呀
I am Li Jing.
我 你静姐
When I just came here,
你说我刚过来的时候吧
Meng'an was having a rest.
梦安正在保胎呢
It is still a question mark
那胎保得住保不住
if the baby can be kept.
还是个问号
They didnt allow me to tell others,
人家不让我跟别人说
not a single one,
谁都不说
and I didnt want to gossip.
我也怕人家嫌我多嘴
But afterwards,
可是后来
when I heard that they were
我就听他们说
deciding not to keep the baby,
说不太想要这个孩子了
it suddenly occurred to me
我就一下子我就在想
that the reason Ouyang
你说当时咱家老爷子
married into
当时把欧阳姐夫
the Li Family
招成上门女婿
was to raise offspring
那不就是要给咱家
to our family!
传宗接代呢吗
If...
如
If the baby of Meng'an
如果梦安肚子里怀的
is a boy,
是个男孩
and they're aborting it,
他们如果不要了
I'll be damned
你说这么大的事
if I don't tell you
我要是不告诉你
what happened!
我对不起您呀 姐
That's what I mean.
所以我说呀
You did a good merit,
你立功了
right?
是吧
Good virtues are not her privilege,
不光梦安懂礼数
but I, Li Jing,
你姐我
also have them.
也懂礼数
Come on.
来吧
This
这个
is the red envelope for you.
姐给你个红包
No way!
不行 不行 不行
Stop!
停
It's my reward for you!
这是姐奖励你的
Take it,
拿着
or I'll be angry with you.
要不然我翻脸了啊
Just take it.
拿着 拿着
Thanks a lot.
谢谢姐
Well,
那个
do you have the address
梦心生孩子
where Mengxin delivered her baby?
那个医院的地址你有吗
Send it to me.
发给我
Are you going there?
你去啊
Of course.
是啊
It's a joyful event to have a baby.
生孩子是大喜事
We should show our virtues,
咱得懂礼数
don't we?
对吧
Mom.
妈
Wait for a moment,
你就等一会儿
and don't come in.
别进来了啊
Take them out, mom.
妈 把这拿出去
Be careful.
轻点
Close the door.
关门了 妈
Mengxin,
心
here are your favorite sweets!
米粿买回来喽
So yummy!
好香啊
I don't want it.
不想吃
What a waste!
真可惜啊 真是
Hello,
你好
is this the room of Xu Mengxin?
这个是许梦心的房间吗
Yes.
是啊
Who are you?
你谁啊
You must be her matron!
你是月嫂吧
These are fruits for Mengxin.
这是给心心送的水果
Wash them later
一会儿 洗一洗
for Mengxin.
给心心吃
Wait.
你等等
Who on earth are you?
你到底谁呀你啊
You won't understand.
我说了你也不懂
How couldn't I?
我怎么不懂啊
Are you speaking a foreign language?
你说的是外语啊
I do apologize.
不好意思 不好意思啊
Well,
那个
you must
您是
be the baby's grandma, aren't you?
这孩子的奶奶 对吧
Sorry for my stupidity!
有眼不识泰山啊
I do apologize.
有眼不识泰山
I hope you can forgive me.
不好意思 不好意思
Darling,
媳妇
it's still warm. Have a taste.
热的呢 尝尝
I'll take a snap.
我要睡觉
Okay.
好嘞
If you want to sleep,
我老婆要睡觉
I'll be there for you.
我陪着你
Eat it after you're awake.
等咱睡会儿再吃
So tell me.
那你告诉我
Who on earth are you?
你到底是谁
I am Li Jing,
我叫李静
the sister of Li Lin,
是李临的姐姐
who is the husband of Meng'an,
李临是梦安的老公
the sister of Mengxin.
梦安是梦心的亲姐姐
Fine, I get it.
我知道了 知道了
Sister-in-law of the Xu Family.
老许家亲家姐姐
There you go,
对
my dear sister!
老姐姐
You're so clever!
这一下就全对了
Wait!
停
How could you call me sister?
你会不会论辈啊
I'm not your dear sister!
你跟谁叫老姐姐呢
I'm Xiongxiong's grandmother,
我是熊熊的奶奶
while you are his
你是熊熊的
distant aunt!
一表三千里的大姑
You should call me...
你应该叫我
Auntie!
大姨
Right.
对对对
You're my auntie.
叫大姨 叫大姨
The yummy sweets
这么好吃的米粿
are still warm.
还是热的呢
Let me explain it to you.
大姨 我跟你说啊
Meng'an
我们家梦安
is pregnant,
不是怀孕了吗
so I'll take care of her.
我来照顾梦安
Meng'an told me about Mengxin,
梦安跟我说 梦心生了
so I rushed over here
我就赶紧得来看看
to take a piece of luck.
沾点喜气啊
A piece of luck.
沾点喜气
You see,
你看
it's a present
给宝贝
for our dear baby.
还送了个小物件
How blessed you are!
大姨 您真有福气啊
A boy and a girl
一子一女
make up the word "blessing".
凑一个好
Fine. Follow me.
行 那你跟我进去吧
I'll put it aside.
我把东西放边上啊
Auntie,
来来来 大姨
I'll take it.
我来 我来
Go away!
你走
Okay.
好好好
Follow me.
跟我进来吧